themoviedb.org 2019-11-23

# Privacy Policy — The Movie Database (TMDb)

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to our website located at https://www.themoviedb.org (the 'website'). This website is operated by TiVo Platform Technologies, LLC and/or its corporate affiliates (“TPT”).

Review TPT’s legal and privacy notices for details on how we collect, use and protect your personal information on this website.

Your use of this website or any software application or service owned by TPT ('TPT Property(ies)') is subject to this privacy policy. This privacy policy explains the data that we collect and how we use it.

We respect your privacy. If you have any privacy concerns or questions about this privacy policy, you can contact us by email at: [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com?subject=TMDb%20Privacy%20Policy)

**Contents**

**ABOUT US AND THIS POLICY**

All references to "we", "us" or "our" refer to TPT and/or one or more of its corporate affiliates.

TPT is a Delaware limited liability company, with offices at 2160 Gold Street, San Jose, CA 95002, United States.

This policy gives you the details of who we are and the details of our privacy policies, including: what data we collect about you when you use a TPT Property; what organization is collecting the information; how the information will be used or disclosed; what choices are available to you regarding the collection and use of the data; what security measures are in place to protect your personal information; and how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. Information collected or provided by or to us may be shared with and used by any of our affiliates in accordance with this Privacy Policy as if the relevant affiliate was 'we' 'us' or 'our' in this Policy.

This policy may be amended from time to time without notice and it is your responsibility to read it carefully and review any changes that may have been made. Since changes will be posted on this page, we encourage you to check this page regularly.

This policy, and the processing of your online account data and any other data we collect, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California. Any related disputes shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in the County of Santa Clara, California.

**YOUR INFORMATION: WHAT WE COLLECT, HOW WE COLLECT IT, AND HOW IT IS USED**

In common with most other websites and on-line services, we collect certain data about your visit to the TPT Properties. Any data we gather through your use of a TPT Property falls into three categories: (1) personal information that you supply to us, such as information you provide when you register (including your e-mail address), create an account, create a username, register your device, complete a survey, enter a contest, or purchase products or services; (2) information that is collected as you use a TPT Property that becomes associated with your personal information; and (3) information that does not directly identify you and is collected as you use TPT Property, including your IP address, and information gathered with the use of a "cookie" (cookies are discussed further below), and information related to searches or recommendations in connection with a TPT Property. Such information includes, without limitation, which pages and content are browsed, interactions with advertising and content, and other data related to preferences and usage. We use this information to, among other things, provide our services to you, create new products and services, and target advertising and content (on our and our business associates' websites) to generate statistics, reports and for various analytic purposes (including combining the data we collect with data from other sources).

You may use certain TPT Properties without registering or creating an account. We may nonetheless build a history of your interactions with a TPT Property even though we don't know who you are.

Regarding TPT Properties that are products, TPT may also employ update management software to collect installation and registry information from your computer, including product, version, build, language and original equipment manufacturer. When you use multiple TPT Properties, TPT may combine or link information collected from various TPT Properties and use it for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy.

**Personal information**

As is common across websites, to use certain features of a TPT Property we may ask you to register, create an account, provide your full name and email address and create a password. Once you have created an account, you will have the option to fill out a form to create your profile (all or portions of the information you submit may be included in your profile). When you create your profile, we collect personal information about you, such as name, address, location, e-mail address, favorite actors, music, etc., which will be stored in order to provide services to you and to conduct other activities including, without limitation, processing your registration, maintaining a profile about you, processing your request to receive newsletters and email announcements, or to voluntarily participate in surveys or contests, and/or communicating with you about services and products we think may be of interest to you.

TPT may allow you to set up a public profile that may be viewed by other users of the TPT Properties. You may choose to include some personal information in your public profile so that other users can identify you. You should only include information in your public profile that you do not mind making publicly available without restriction.

To process your purchase orders we require your name, billing address, phone number, e-mail address, shipping address, credit card information and credit card security codes. We use this information to process your order(s) and, if any questions arise, to contact you about your order(s). We may also use it to contact you about other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. In general, TPT will first try to e-mail you, but may contact you by phone or send an electronic message to you if you have provided these details and your consent to such contact.

Personal information is also used to provide personalized services to you, such as show tracking and recommendations.

We may provide data about our users, traffic patterns, products, services and site information to third-parties (such as vendors, advertisers and our business associates) ("Third Parties"), but, except as otherwise described in this policy, we will use reasonable efforts to provide it in a form that does not directly identify you.

**Creation of Anonymous Data.**  We may create anonymous data records from your personal information ("Anonymous Data") by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the data personally identifiable to you. Once we create Anonymous Data, this Anonymous Data becomes our property. We use this Anonymous Data in many ways including analyzing user request and usage patterns, creating reports and performing analytics so that we may enhance the content of our services, improving site navigation and providing meaningful analysis of habits, usage, trends, and effectiveness of marketing campaigns, etc. as part of our products and services. TPT reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties in its absolute discretion.

**Social Media and Profiles.**  For certain TPT Properties, the information that we may ask you to provide could include name, gender, location, e-mail address, biographical information and the movies and television shows that you like to watch. When you create your profile, you may be asked if you want your profile to be public or private. Unless you state that you want your profile to be private, your profile will be available for public viewing.

**Public Content.**  Your photos, posts, friends, and other content you post to the TPT Properties (and your profile if you designate it as public, including your first name and last initial but excluding any other account registration information) are meant for public consumption. We may display this content on the TPT Properties and further distribute it to a wider audience through third party sites and services.

**Facebook and other Social Networking Sites.**  If you are logged into Facebook or another social networking site ("SNS") that we support, and you access but are not logged into the TPT Property, we may receive information from Facebook or the SNS to make it easier for you to create an account on the TPT Property and to show our relevant content from your Facebook or SNS friends. This information personalizes your experience and helps you create an account (where this option is available). You may also be able to connect your account on the TPT Property to your accounts on Facebook or other SNSs, in which case we may collect and store information identifying your account with the third party service. We use this information to help you connect and share public content with your friends and followers.

**Material You Choose to Reveal in On-line Fora, Blogs, Message Boards, Chat Rooms or Similar Locations.**  You may be able to post personal information on areas of a TPT Property that may be viewed by other users or the public, although we recommend that you do not do so. Please note that there are risks, including but not limited to the risk of physical harm, of dealing with strangers, including persons who may be acting under false pretenses. Please choose carefully the information you post on the TPT Property and that you give to other TPT Property users. You are discouraged from publicly posting your full name, telephone numbers, street addresses or other information that identifies you or allows strangers to find you or steal your identity. Be aware that other people's information may be offensive, harmful or inaccurate, and in some cases will be mislabeled or deceptively labeled.

**YOU ASSUME ALL RISKS ASSOCIATED WITH DEALING WITH OTHER USERS WITH WHOM YOU COME IN CONTACT THROUGH TPT PROPERTIES. WE EXPECT THAT YOU WILL USE CAUTION AND COMMON SENSE WHEN USING TPT PROPERTIES.**

**Tracking and Cookies**

When you visit TPT websites and other TPT Properties, we and our advertising associates may store and access information from your device, including "cookies", clear GIFs (which are also sometimes called web bugs or web beacons) and browser details. We may collect information such as your browser type, the type of operating system you use, the domain name of your Internet service provider, IP address, pages visited on the site, services used and how you have used them. We and our advertising associates do this for a variety of purposes. In the case of our advertising associates, this may include the personalization of advertisements based on your visits to sites in that party's network. Please note that TPT Properties do not currently respond to a web browser's "do not track" instructions (e.g., a "do not track" signal). However, Google analytics manages 'Do Not Track' instructions from your browser in accordance with its own privacy policies: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

**Consent for the use of cookies**

_If you continue to use this TPT Property,_ _you consent to our use of cookies._

**TPT E-mail**

E-mail addresses are used for identification, inviting new friends to TPT Properties, searching for and finding friends, general communication, order processing and to send notifications to you. To facilitate searching for and finding friends on the TPT Properties, TPT allows users to search for other members using text searches, first and last name, email address, and by using other attributes. Users can invite friends to join certain TPT Properties by e-mailing invitations via our automated invitation system. Where permitted by applicable law, TPT stores these email addresses so that the respondents may be added to the friend list of the member sending the invitations and to establish relationships between users.

**WHICH ORGANIZATIONS ARE COLLECTING THE INFORMATION?**

When you provide information to TPT, that information is collected and maintained either by TPT or by an authorized agent or contractor of TPT, including, without limitation, web hosting companies, customer care service providers, and/or transaction processing service providers, unless specifically stated otherwise at the point of collection.

**ADVERTISING**

We may use your personal information and non-personal information to serve ads to you via a TPT Property, as well as to provide you with promotions, products and services. We may also use third-party advertising companies and other business associates to serve ads on TPT Property or other sites and provide you with promotions, products and services. These third-party advertising companies and our business associates may be located throughout the world.

These third-party advertising companies and business associates may receive and share with us information relating to the advertisements that they serve you including, without limitation, date and time of ad shown, the ad that was shown, your IP address and your interactions with such advertisements. These third-party advertising companies and business associates may use cookies, clear GIFs and anonymous information about your visits to TPT Property and other websites to measure and improve the effectiveness of their ads, promotions, products and services. This information may also be used for targeted marketing purposes. The information received by these third-party advertising companies and business associates is subject to the privacy policies of these third-party advertising companies and business associates. We may be given access to this information by these third-party advertising companies and business associates which we may use for purposes including, without limitation, to provide services to you, to better target advertising and content to you and to generate statistics and reports and to carry out analytics that help us to provide our services, to create new products and services, to better target advertising and content, (on our and our business associates' websites, applications and devices) to generate statistics, reports and for various analytic purposes. We may make certain information about you available to third-party advertising companies and other business associates under agreements between us and those third-party advertising companies and business associates. The third-party advertising companies and business associates will use that information to target advertising to you or provide and market promotions, products and services to you. You may withdraw your consent to our sending your personal information to advertising companies and business associates by sending us a written e-mail request from the e-mail address that is registered with us. If you do so, we will no longer provide your personal information from the relevant TPT Property to third party advertisers or business associates. However, where permitted by applicable law, we may still provide them with information that does not directly identify you and they may send you targeted advertisements.

Many of our advertising associates are part of the Network Advertising Initiative. You may opt-out of behavioral advertising for Network Advertising Initiative member companies by following the link below and opting-out of all or some of the advertising networks: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

Opting out of Flash Cookies is described above in the tracking information section.

**SECURITY & RETENTION POLICIES**

We use commercially reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. However, due to the design of the Internet, ever-changing technology and other factors outside of our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties or that we will not be subject to security breaches. To the extent permitted by law, we will have no liability for the disclosure of personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized or unlawful acts of third parties.

You are responsible for the security of your user name, ID and password for any of the TPT Properties. Please take care when using and storing them and let us know immediately if you lose them or suspect they are compromised.

Our practice is to retain your personal data for so long as we believe it is relevant to us. We may retain your personal data for up to 3 years from the last interaction with you. Anonymous Data is not subject to this retention practice and we may keep and use it indefinitely.

**COMMITMENT TO CHILDRENS' PRIVACY**

Protecting the privacy of children is important to us. For that reason, none of our TPT Properties are directed at anyone under 13 and they are not structured specifically to attract anyone under 13. We also do not collect or maintain personal information from those users who we actually know are under 13. Should we learn or be notified that we have collected information from users under the age of 13, we will immediately delete such personal information.

If you are under 18 and wish to delete information attributed to you from our TPT Properties please contact [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com?subject=TMDb%20Privacy%20Policy) with details of your request.

**UNSUBSCRIBING AND OPTING OUT**

When you register to access certain TPT Properties, you provide us with personal information for us to contact you (including sending you marketing material). You can let us know that you do not wish to receive announcements or marketing material from us by either e-mailing us (from the account registered with us) with a written request to opt out of receiving further materials from us or opting out from the marketing material by using the 'unsubscribe' function in these marketing materials. If you opt out or do not provide your personal information then some services and features (such as personal information services, recommendations and tracking of ratings and likes and dislikes) may not be available to you or may be deleted. All newsletters and e-mail announcements from us will contain an unsubscribe link that also allows you to opt out at any time from these messages.

**Review and Correction**

Where you have registered to access certain TPT Properties, you may review and update the personal information that you have provided to us by visiting the set up page of the relevant TPT Property and updating your account profile (where this function exists) or e-mailing your request for change from the email account that is registered with us.

**OTHER DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will not otherwise use or disclose your personal information without your consent except (i) as described in this privacy policy, (ii) as required by court order or other government or law enforcement authorities in order to comply with legal process or law, (iii) in the event of a merger where another company has acquired the relevant TPT Property, (iv) in order to protect against the misuse or unauthorized use of TPT Property, (v) in order to protect and defend our rights and property, or (vi) in order to protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public.

If TPT sells assets (or the assets of a division or subsidiary) to another entity, including, without limitation, in the event of bankruptcy, or if TPT (or a division or subsidiary) is acquired by, or merged with, another entity, TPT may provide to such entity user information (both anonymized and/or aggregate and personal information) that is related to that part of the business that was sold to or merged with the other entity.

**Links to Third Party Websites**

TPT Properties may display links to websites operated by third parties. If you click on a link, the relevant third party operator or others may collect data about you when you visit the linked website. They are responsible for the collection and further processing of such data and we have no control over it. We advise you to check the terms of use and privacy policies of any linked websites you visit to find out what data they are collecting and the purposes for which they process your personal data.

**OVERSEAS TRANSFERS AND PROCESSING OF YOUR INFORMATION**

**Transfer to USA and other Jurisdictions**

TPT data is managed from offices in several countries and your personal information may be transferred to any of these jurisdictions. Whenever TPT transfers personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area in the course of sharing information as set out herein, we will ensure that the information is transferred in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as permitted by the applicable laws on data protection.

If we send your personal information overseas, the recipients are required to store and use it only in accordance with TPT’s data policies. TPT may make your personal information available to government authorities when required by law.

If you have any inquiries or complaints about our handling of your personal information, or about our privacy practices generally, please contact us at: [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com?subject=TMDb%20Privacy%20Policy). We will respond to your inquiry promptly.

**YOUR CONSENT**

**BY USING ANY TPT PROPERTIES, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR INFORMATION DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

**YOUR RIGHTS**

**Your European Rights**

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area ("EEA"), then in respect of your personal information collected and held by TPT, you have the right to:

  * access the personal information we process on you;

  * request restriction of our use;

  * rectify inaccuracies in the personal information;

  * deny or withdraw your consent to all or some of our use of your personal information collected by us;

  * lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority;

  * subject to the anonymous data paragraph above, deletion of your personal information from our system of records. However, in such event we may not be able respond to or engage further with your enquiry with the company

TPT aims to keep its records about you as accurate as possible. If you would like to review, change or delete details you have supplied us with or wish to exercise any of your other rights, please contact us as set out below.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you in this Privacy Policy with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt-out (or "unsubscribe") of our use and sharing of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please send a request by email to our Privacy Administrator at privacy@ tivo.com or by postal mail to TPT, 2160 Gold Street, San Jose, CA 95002, United States. Attn: Your California Privacy Rights, c/o Privacy Administrator, Legal Department. All requests must be labelled "Your California Privacy Rights" in the e-mail subject line or envelope or post card. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights", include your name, street address, city, state, zip code and e-mail address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via e-mail) and indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (e-mail or postal mail). We are unable to accept requests via telephone or by facsimile. We are not responsible for notices that are not labelled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

**Inquiries**

If you have any concern about privacy at TPT, please send us a thorough description of your concern to [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com?subject=TMDb%20Privacy%20Policy) or the address above, and we will try to resolve it.

**Data Protection Officer**

TiVo Corporation ("TiVo"), located at 2160 Gold Street, San Jose, CA 95002, United States, is the data controller for your personal information. Any questions that you have concerning this Privacy Policy or TPT's collection and use of personal information should be addressed to TPT's data protection officer, who can be contacted at [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com?subject=TMDb%20Privacy%20Policy).

If the TPT data protection officer for EMEA region is unable to help you, we suggest you refer to your local privacy regulator for help. For example, in the UK that would be the information commissioner's office at - https://ico.org.uk/.

TPT’s businesses change regularly, and so may our privacy policy. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our policy's terms and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our website frequently for any changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you. Please check our privacy policy on a regular basis.

This privacy policy was last updated on: July 26, 2019.
